<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: visualizations | Edwin Chen's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://echen.github.com/blog/categories/visualizations/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echen.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-05T21:06:15-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://echen.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Edwin Chen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visualizing Miss USA 2011: Should Evolution be Taught in Schools?]]></title>
    <link href="http://echen.github.com/blog/2011/07/09/visualizing-miss-usa-2011-should-evolution-be-taught-in-schools/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-09T13:02:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://echen.github.com/blog/2011/07/09/visualizing-miss-usa-2011-should-evolution-be-taught-in-schools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>tl;dr</strong> Should evolution be taught in schools? Go <a href="http://miss-usa-evolution.heroku.com">here</a> to visualize what the Miss USA contestants think.</p>

<h1>The Visualization</h1>

<p>Education is an area sorely in need of data crunching, so when I ran across <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9QBv2CFTSWU&amp;feature=player_embedded#at=56">an amusing video</a> satirizing the Miss USA contestants' thoughts on teaching evolution, I thought it would be fun to transcribe <a href="youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UkBmhM0R2A0&amp;feature=youtu.be#at=41">the original video</a> and visualize the data.</p>

<p>So after some tedious transcription, I built <a href="http://miss-usa-evolution.heroku.com">this app</a> to categorize and visualize the responses in various ways. (Mouseover states to see transcriptions, and click to jump to each contestant's response in the video.)</p>

<h1>Example Maps</h1>

<p>Here are some examples of the generated maps.</p>

<p>First, we can look at which contestants believe in evolution (Miss California -- the winner! -- is the only contestant who explicitly states she believes in evolution; the red states explicitly state they do not believe in evolution; the grey states don't make clear what they believe):</p>

<p><a href="http://miss-usa-evolution.heroku.com/?column=believes"><img src="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/blog/miss-usa-evolution/believe-evolution.png" alt="Believe Evolution" /></a></p>

<p>We can also see which contestants believe evolution should be taught in schools (green states say yes, red states say no, grey states say maybe or that it should be a choice):</p>

<p><a href="http://miss-usa-evolution.heroku.com/?column=should_teach"><img src="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/blog/miss-usa-evolution/teach-evolution.png" alt="Teach Evolution" /></a></p>

<p>Here is a rough Darwin-friendliness score I assigned to each response (worst in dark red to best in dark green):</p>

<p><a href="http://miss-usa-evolution.heroku.com/?column=score"><img src="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/blog/miss-usa-evolution/score.png" alt="Score" /></a></p>

<p>This map shows which contestants believe schools should teach creationism:</p>

<p><a href="http://miss-usa-evolution.heroku.com/?column=teach_creationism"><img src="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/blog/miss-usa-evolution/teach-creationism.png" alt="Teach Creationism" /></a></p>

<p>And this map shows which contestants mention science in their response:</p>

<p><a href="http://miss-usa-evolution.heroku.com/?column=mentions_science"><img src="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/blog/miss-usa-evolution/mention-science.png" alt="Mention Science" /></a></p>

<p>So while there aren't any striking patterns (I was hoping for a bright swath of red across the most religious states), the data's still fun to look at, and it's helpful to see that Alabama, whose <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UkBmhM0R2A0&amp;feature=youtu.be#at=42">strongly anti-evolution</a> candidate is the only one colored red in both of the first two maps, does seem to be a bit of an outlier with respect to the rest of the nation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eigensheep]]></title>
    <link href="http://echen.github.com/blog/2011/05/01/eigensheep/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-01T15:23:31-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://echen.github.com/blog/2011/05/01/eigensheep</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aaron Koblin's <a href="http://www.thesheepmarket.com/">Sheep Market</a> visualization is an awesome use of Mechanical Turk. But it'd be even more awesome if the grid were <em>ordered</em>, so I decided to try projecting the sheep onto two dimensions.</p>

<h1>Principal Sheep Components</h1>

<p>After screenshotting the first 50 sheep from the market and normalizing their size and color, here's what a PCA projection looks like (<a href="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/eigensheep.png">click</a> for a larger view):</p>

<p><a href="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/eigensheep.png"><img src="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/eigensheep.png" alt="Projected Sheep" /></a></p>

<p>Notice how the stroke widths get thicker as we move to the right (i.e., <strong>the first principal component seems to measure the blackness of the sheep</strong>), and the amount of wool on the sheep's body increases as we move up (i.e., <strong>the second principal component seems to measure the wooliness of the sheep</strong>).</p>

<p>It's also pretty neat how all the sheep with black heads and black legs (sheep 35, 16, 32, 31, and 19) get clumped together:</p>

<p><a href="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/eigensheep-black-heads.png"><img src="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/10506/eigensheep-black-heads.png" alt="Projected Sheep, Black Heads/Legs Circled" /></a></p>

<p>And I think the sheep on the left (next to and inside the dense cluster) seem much more poorly drawn -- they look more like camels, dogs, unicorns, or bugs than actual sheep.</p>

<h1>Code</h1>

<p>In a bit more detail, I used the poor man's Mechanical Turk (myself) to screenshot the first 50 sheep from the market, trying to hug the sheep as closely as possible to ensure proper alignment. Next, I used the <a href="http://www.pythonware.com/products/pil/">Python Imaging Library</a> to resize the images to 150x150px, convert them to grayscale, and flatten them into the rows of a matrix.</p>

<p>In case anyone else wants to play with the sheep images, I put the <a href="https://github.com/echen/eigensheep">code</a> on my <a href="https://github.com/echen/eigensheep">Github</a> account.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Piiikaaachuuuuuu vs. KHAAAAAN!]]></title>
    <link href="http://echen.github.com/blog/2011/03/14/piiikaaachuuuuuu-vs-khaaaaan/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-14T04:26:14-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://echen.github.com/blog/2011/03/14/piiikaaachuuuuuu-vs-khaaaaan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fun image:</p>

<p><a href="(http://www.flickr.com/photos/squidnews/3200285750/"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3134/3200285750_d2bd0a62fd.jpg" alt="KH(Ax)N" /></a></p>

<p>But I've never actually watched any of the Star Trek movies, so I decided to recreate the graph with Pikachu instead:</p>

<p><a href="https://img.skitch.com/20110224-1x8ptj7bbajk6an2xj462w7jb.jpg"><img src="https://img.skitch.com/20110224-1x8ptj7bbajk6an2xj462w7jb.jpg" alt="pikachu-graph1" /></a></p>

<p>Here's a smoothed version to better compare the counts between different letters:</p>

<p><a href="https://img.skitch.com/20110224-1w8xnbfi3s3tmgexupmw1s2kxu.jpg"><img src="https://img.skitch.com/20110224-1w8xnbfi3s3tmgexupmw1s2kxu.jpg" alt="pikachu-graph2" /></a></p>

<p>Unsurprisingly, people like to elongate the "u" in "pikachu" a lot better than they like to elongate the "a" and "i", though I'm surprised just how many "pikachuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuu"s are out there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
